Guide to the Edwin Montefiore Borchard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject Files: International Law & Foreign Affairs, 1913-1950; Series III; 19' 5" (47 boxes)
  - International law: conferences and miscellaneous research topics
    - Harvard Law School - Research in International Law memorandum on diplomatic protection of citizens abroad, 1930 (Box 97, Folder 949)
    - Research in international law - responsibility of states, 1927-1928 (Box 97, Folder 950-953)
    - Research in international law - responsibility of states, 1929 (Box 98, Folder 954-955)
    - Harvard Law School - Research in International Law memoranda (Box 98, Folder 956)
    - Research in international law - responsibility of states, 1930-1935 (Box 98, Folder 957)
    - "Responsabilité de l'Etat, Espèces ", 1887-1897 (Box 98, Folder 958)
    - Council on Foreign Relations
      - Study Group on Legal Problems of Reconstruction study reports, memorandum, 1943 (Box 98, Folder 959-960)
      - Study Group on Legal Problems of Reconstruction, 1943 (Box 98, Folder 961)
      - Study Group on Legal Problems of Reconstruction, 1943 (Box 99, Folder 962)
      - Study group reports, 1944 (Box 99, Folder 963)
      - Postwar Settlement of Property Rights - report, 1945-1946 (Box 99, Folder 964)
    - Institut International de Rome pour l'Unification du Droit Privé - proceedings, 1938 (Box 99, Folder 965)
    - Commission of Experts on the Codification of International Law - documents, 1938 (Box 99, Folder 966-967)
    - International Law Association - Private Property Committee Report, 1930 (Box 99, Folder 968)
    - "Die Bodenreform in der Tschechoslovakei" von Dr. L. von Ruttkay (Box 99, Folder 969)
    - Pan American Day - memos by William Manger, 1938 (Box 99, Folder 970)
    - Legal bibliographies - American and foreign (Box 99, Folder 971)
    - International law research project proposal, 1938-1941 (Box 100, Folder 972)
    - International law - research materials, memoranda, 1940-1941 (Box 100, Folder 973)
    - International law - memoranda, pamphlets (Box 100, Folder 974)
    - International Academy of Comparative Law, The Hague, 1935-1938 (Box 100, Folder 975)
    - The future of international law and postwar inter national organization - memoranda, 1940's (Box 100, Folder 976-977)
    - Limitation of armaments - newspaper clippings (Box 100, Folder 978)
    - American Society of International Law - Section on Codification, 1938-1942 (Box 100, Folder 979)
    - Institute of International Law, Cambridge, 1930-1933 (Box 101, Folder 980-981)
    - Institute of International Law - Oslo Session 1932
      - Notes (Box 101, Folder 982)
      - Diplomatic protection of foreigners (Box 101, Folder 983)
      - Diplomatic protection of foreigners - memoranda (French text) (Box 101, Folder 984-985)
    - Institute of International Law, Luxembourg, 1937 (Box 101, Folder 986)
- Subject Files: U.S. Law and Politics, 1915-1950; Series IV; 16' (38 boxes)
  Subject files are grouped in four sections according to subject. Materials within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  Section A: Declaratory judgments
  Section B: Convicting the innocent
  Section C: American neutrality
  Section D: Miscellaneous research topics
  - Declaratory Judgments
    - Declaratory judgments: correspondence, 1919-1931 (Box 102, Folder 987-994)
    - Declaratory judgments: correspondence, 1932-1935 April (Box 103, Folder 995-1002)
    - Declaratory judgments: correspondence, 1935 May-1939 May, 1937 July-1939 (Box 104, Folder 1003-1011)
    - Declaratory judgments, 1940-1944 (Box 105, Folder 1012-1019)
    - Declaratory judgments, 1945, 1947 (Box 106, Folder 1020-1022)
    - Declaratory Judgments: correspondence
      - re: Revision, 1940-1946 (Box 106, Folder 1023-1026)
      - re: Second revision, 1941-1945 (Box 106, Folder 1027)
    - Declaratory judgments: research notes and memoranda
      - Tileston v. Ullman, 1942-1943 (Box 106, Folder 1028)
      - Aetna Life v. Haworth, 1937 (Box 106, Folder 1029)
      - Reed v. Littleton, 1937-1939 (Box 106, Folder 1030)
      - research notes, memoranda (Box 107, Folder 1031-1034)
      - research notes (Box 107, Folder 1035-1038)
      - research notes (Box 108, Folder 1039-1044)
      - Colegrove v. Green - research notes (Box 108, Folder 1045-1046)
      - Miles Lab v. F.T.C., 1943-1944 (Box 109, Folder 1047-1049)
    - Convicting the Innocent
      - Bill for indemnity for errors of criminal justice, 1934-1946 (Box 109, Folder 1050-1053)
      - Research notes, memoranda (Box 110, Folder 1054-1055)
      - Case newspaper clippings (Box 110, Folder 1056)
    - Convicting the Innocent
      - reviews, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 1057-1058)
      - case newspaper clippings (Box 110, Folder 1059-1061)
      - miscellaneous research materials (Box 110, Folder 1062)
      - research materials - statutes, miscellaneous (Box 111, Folder 1063)
      - Criminal justice bibliography (Box 111, Folder 1064)
      - Correspondence, 1929-1931 July (Box 111, Folder 1065-1070)
      - Correspondence, 1931 August - 1934 (Box 112, Folder 1071-1078)
      - Correspondence, 1935-1947 (Box 113, Folder 1079-1082)
      - Correspondence - Blazenzitz Case (Box 113, Folder 1083)
      - Correspondence - Alice G. Douglas (Box 113, Folder 1084)
    - Research cases
      - Andrews, Herbert T.- Massachusetts (Box 113, Folder 1085)
      - Barbera, Anthony-New York (Box 113, Folder 1085)
      - Beck, Adolf- England (Box 113, Folder 1085)
      - Berner, Mary - Illinois (Box 113, Folder 1086)
      - Boyd, Payne - West Virginia (Box 113, Folder 1086)
      - Broughton, William - Georgia (Box 113, Folder 1086)
      - Brown, J. B. - Florida (Box 114, Folder 1087)
      - Butler, Louise and Yelder, George - Alabama (Box 114, Folder 1087)
      - Chance, John H. - Massachusetts (Box 114, Folder 1087)
      - Chesterman, John - Massachusetts (Box 114, Folder 1088)
      - Collins, Benjamin F. - Massachusetts (Box 114, Folder 1088)
      - Dabney, Conday - Kentucky (Box 114, Folder 1088)
      - Evans and Ledbetter - California (Box 114, Folder 1089)
      - Flood, Floyd - Illinois (Box 114, Folder 1089)
      - "Frenchy", Ameer Ben Ali - New York (Box 114, Folder 1089)
      - Galino, Hernandel, Mendival - California (Box 114, Folder 1090)
      - Gangi, Cero - Massachusetts (Box 114, Folder 1090)
      - Greenwald, Irving - New york (Box 114, Folder 1090)
      - Gunter, Thomas - Mississippi (Box 114, Folder 1091)
      - Habton, William - England (Box 114, Folder 1091)
      - Hess and Craig - Missouri (Box 114, Folder 1091)
      - Hicks, Edward L. - Missouri Federal (Box 114, Folder 1092)
      - Hinkley - Massachusetts (Box 114, Folder 1092)
      - Hoffman, Harry L. - New York (Box 114, Folder 1092)
      - Howell, Everett - Illinois (Box 114, Folder 1092)
      - Howell, Frank - West Virginia (Box 114, Folder 1092)
      - Israel, Harold - Connecticut (Box 114, Folder 1093)
      - Jacobs, Elmer P. - California (Box 114, Folder 1093)
      - Johnson, John A. - Wisconsin (Box 114, Folder 1093)
      - Kimball, Edward A. - Maryland (Box 114, Folder 1094)
      - Klass, Louis - Minnesota (Box 114, Folder 1094)
      - Krueger, Oscar - New York Federal (Box 114, Folder 1094)
      - Lambert, Henry - Maine (Box 115, Folder 1095)
      - Lee, Hugh C. - Georgia Federal (Box 115, Folder 1096)
      - Lesher, Garvey and Rohan - California (Box 115, Folder 1096)
      - Lyons, Ernest - Virginia (Box 115, Folder 1096)
      - Lyons, Ernest - Virginia (Box 115, Folder 1097)
      - McCauley, Alexander - New York (Box 115, Folder 1098)
      - McDonald, John - Ohio (Box 115, Folder 1098)
      - MacGregor, Robert - Michigan (Box 115, Folder 1098)
      - McKinney, Clarence Leroy - Ohio (Box 115, Folder 1098)
      - McManus, John - Massachusetts (Box 115, Folder 1099)
      - Manners, George - England (Box 115, Folder 1099)
      - Murchison, John - Alabama (Box 115, Folder 1100)
      - Nedza, Joseph - New York (Box 115, Folder 1101)
      - Olson, Henry - Illinois (Box 115, Folder 1101)
      - Pezzulich and Sgelirrach - New York (Box 115, Folder 1101)
      - Philion, Hayter Oscar - Utah (Box 115, Folder 1101)
      - Powell, Willard - Iowa (Box 116, Folder 1102)
      - Preston, James - California (Box 116, Folder 1102)
      - Prevost, Lloyd - Michigan (Box 116, Folder 1102)
      - Purvis Case - Mississippi (Box 116, Folder 1103)
      - Sands, Icie - New York (Box 116, Folder 1104)
      - Shannon and Clements - Texas (Box 116, Folder 1104)
      - Sissons and Sullivan - Washington, D.C. (Box 116, Folder 1104)
      - Slater, Oscar - England (Box 116, Folder 1105)
      - Slyter, George B. - Minnesota (Box 116, Folder 1106)
      - Stain and Cromwell - Maine (Box 116, Folder 1106)
      - Stielow and Green - New York (Box 116, Folder 1106)
      - Sullivan, Percy B. - Indiana Federal (Box 116, Folder 1107)
      - Sweeney, James - New Jersey (Box 116, Folder 1107)
      - The "Sidney Men" (Berdue) - California (Box 116, Folder 1107)
      - Thornton, Lonzo - Ohio (Box 116, Folder 1108)
      - Thorvik and Hughes - Minnesota (Box 116, Folder 1108)
      - Toth, Andrew - Pennsylvania (Box 116, Folder 1108)
      - Usher, Cornelius - Massachusetts (Box 116, Folder 1109)
      - Vaught, Stiles, and Bates (Box 116, Folder 1109)
      - Walker, Moses - Mississippi (Box 116, Folder 1109)
      - Ward, Joseph alias Winston - Massachusetts (Box 116, Folder 1110)
      - Weaver, Joseph - Ohio (Box 116, Folder 1110)
      - Willis, James - California (Box 116, Folder 1110)
      - Wilson, Bill - Alabama (Box 117, Folder 1111)
      - Wood, Sidney - California (Box 117, Folder 1112)
      - Woods and Miller - Arkansas Federal (Box 117, Folder 1112)
      - Zambino, Luigi - New Jersey Federal (Box 117, Folder 1112)
      - Discarded cases (Box 117, Folder 1113-1115)
  - American neutrality
    - Neutrality pamphlets, clippings, circulars, 1930's- 1940's (Box 117, Folder 1116)
    - Neutrality pamphlets, clippings, circulars, 1930's- 1940's (Box 118, Folder 1117-1121)
    - Neutrality for the U.S.
      - research notes & correspondence re: publication (Box 118, Folder 1122)
      - research notes, clippings, memoranda (Box 118, Folder 1123)
      - research notes, clippings, memoranda (Box 119, Folder 1124-1128)
    - Lawyers Committee on American Relations with Spain, 1939
      - memorandum on non-recognition of Franco (Box 119, Folder 1129)
      - correspondence re: Franco government (Box 119, Folder 1129)
    - American neutrality
      - Correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box 119, Folder 1130-1132)
      - Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 120, Folder 1133-1135)
    - America First - miscellaneous handbills (Box 120, Folder 1136)
    - Neutrality Bills, 1940-1941 (Box 120, Folder 1137)
    - Neutrality handbills and memoranda, 1940's (Box 120, Folder 1138)
    - Peace movement handbills and memoranda, 1940's (Box 120, Folder 1139)
  - Miscellaneous research topics
    - Rotholz, Walter - correspondence, 1933, 1937-1943,1945,1947 (Box 120, Folder 1140-1142)
    - Rotholz manuscript - Chapter I (Box 120, Folder 1143)
    - Rotholz manuscript - Chapter II (Box 120, Folder 1144)
    - Rotholz manuscript - Chapter III (Box 120, Folder 1145)
    - Rotholz manuscript - Chapter IV (Box 121, Folder 1146-1147)
    - Rotholz manuscript - Chapters V, VI (Box 121, Folder 1148)
    - Rotholz manuscript - Bibliography (Box 121, Folder 1149)
    - Rotholz manuscript revisions (Box 121, Folder 1150-1153)
    - Rotholz manuscript, revisions (Box 122, Folder 1154-1156)
    - Federal Torts Claim Bill: correspondence & memoranda, 1926-1935 (Box 122, Folder 1157-1162)
    - Federal Torts Claim Bill: correspondence & memoranda, 1936-1941 (Box 123, Folder 1163-1165)
    - State liability for tort
      - Digests, memorandum (Box 123, Folder 1166-1167)
      - Digest, memorandum (Box 123, Folder 1167)
      - Research notes (Box 123, Folder 1168)
      - Federal statutes, Congressional hearings, 1920's (Box 123, Folder 1169-1170)
      - Research notes (Box 123, Folder 1171)
      - Research notes (Box 124, Folder 1172-1176)
    - Young and Ottley, Inc. re: investment policy, 1934-1939 (Box 124, Folder 1177-1178)
    - Investment correspondence, 1940 (Box 124, Folder 1179)
    - Investment correspondence, 1941-1947 (Box 125, Folder 1180-1183)
    - Research Institute in International Law & Relations
      - Preliminary research, 1929 (Box 125, Folder 1184-1186)
      - Preliminary proposals, 1929 (Box 125, Folder 1187-1188)
      - Preliminary correspondence, 1930 (Box 125, Folder 1189)
    - Law School matters, 1919-1921 (Box 126, Folder 1190-1191)
    - Yale Law School
      - Memoranda, notes (Box 126, Folder 1192-1194)
      - International Law course syllabus (Box 126, Folder 1195-1196)
      - Proposal for Institute of International Legal Research (Box 126, Folder 1197)
    - American Bar Association
      - Committee on Communication, 1934-1935 April (Box 126, Folder 1198-1199)
      - Committee on Communication, 1935 May-Aug, 1936-1943 (Box 127, Folder 1200-1207)
      - Committee on Communication, 1944-1946 (Box 128, Folder 1208)
      - Committee on Codification of International Law (Box 128, Folder 1209)
      - Committee on Municipal Tort Liability, 1937-1946 (Box 128, Folder 1210-1215)
    - State Department, 1912, 1913 September-December (Box 128, Folder 1216-1218)
    - State Department, 1914 January-Aug, undated (Box 129, Folder 1219-1226)
    - Citizen's Conference on International Economic union, 1942-1947 (Box 129, Folder 1227-1229)
    - National Foreign Trade Convention, 1942-1943 (Box 130, Folder 1230)
    - National Foreign Trade Council
      - Law Committee - Study on War Claims, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 1231-1232)
      - Subcommittee on Treaties, 1944 (Box 130, Folder 1233)
    - Ross Essay Contest, 1944 (Box 130, Folder 1234-1235)
    - American Political Science Association
      - Committee on Judicial Organization and Administration, 1946-1947 (Box 130, Folder 1236)
      - Section on Constitutional Law, 1942-1944 (Box 130, Folder 1237)
      - Committee Reports, 1933 (Box 130, Folder 1238)
    - St. Lawrence Project, 1944 (Box 131, Folder 1239)
    - St. Lawrence Project, 1946-1947 (Box 131, Folder 1240)
    - Legal Bibliography (Box 131, Folder 1241-1242)
    - Supreme Court packing, 1937 (Box 131, Folder 1243-1244)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1940-1944 (Box 131, Folder 1245)
    - Curricula vitae - German refugee professors (Box 131, Folder 1246)
    - "Delegation of Powers and Judicial Review" by Sidney B. Jacoby (Box 131, Folder 1247)
    - Plan for chain of peoples' colleges by William H. Kilpatrick (Box 131, Folder 1248)
    - Institute of Politics - Eighth Session - round Table No. 1 - Protection of Citizens Abroad, 1928 (Box 132, Folder 1249)
    - Research on evidence, 1930, 1935 (Box 132, Folder 1250)
    - John Bassett Moore - "The Bronco of the West" (typescript poem) (Box 132, Folder 1251)
    - John Bassett Moore bibliography, 1931 (Box 132, Folder 1251)
    - Bilder and Bilder re: Morris Colton, 1932 (Box 132, Folder 1252)
    - Crecraft, Earl Willis re: Freedom of the Seas, 1933-1936 (Box 132, Folder 1253)
    - Common Council for American Unity "Interpreter Releases", 1942 (Box 132, Folder 1254)
    - "Der Unterhaltsanspruch ehelicher Kindergegen den ehelichen Vater im deutschen Recht" (Box 132, Folder 1255)
    - "Some Considerations Affecting the Peace Settlement with Germany" by Arnold Wolfers, 1940 (Box 132, Folder 1256)
    - Concessionary Contracts in International Law; The Problem of the Just War in International Law by von Elbe (Box 132, Folder 1257)
    - Town Meeting of the Air, 1944 (Box 132, Folder 1258)
    - Eighth American Scientific Conference, 1940 (Box 132, Folder 1259)
    - Institute of World Polity, 1944-1947 (Box 132, Folder 1260)
    - National Foreign Trade Council Law Committee - Subcommittee on Industrial Property Patents, 1945-1946 (Box 133, Folder 1261)
    - Money and the Law Institute, 1945 (Box 133, Folder 1262)
    - Correspondence re: "Treaties and Executive Agreements", 1945-1946 (Box 133, Folder 1263)
    - Library of Congress, 1945-1946 (Box 133, Folder 1264)
    - Foundation for Foreign Affairs, 1945-1947 (Box 133, Folder 1265)
    - Perfection Building and Loan Association, 1938 (Box 133, Folder 1266)
    - Morrison, Phoebe- resume (Box 133, Folder 1267)
    - Morgenthau, Hans L. - resume, 1937 (Box 133, Folder 1268)
    - Herz, Dr. Hans - resume, 1939 (Box 133, Folder 1269)
    - Encyclopedia of International Law proposals, 1939-1940 (Box 133, Folder 1270)
    - Re: The Philosophy, of Silence by Alice Borchard Greene, 1937-1942 (Box 133, Folder 1271)
    - N.R.A. - briefs on telegraph code (Box 133, Folder 1272)
    - Political handbills and circular letters - misc., 1930's, 1940's (Box 133, Folder 1273)
    - Rushton v. Schram, 1944 (Box 134, Folder 1274)
    - Starr v. Schram, 1943-1944 (Box 134, Folder 1274)
    - Pradlick v. Connecticut, 1944-1945 (Box 134, Folder 1275-1276)
    - New York Post v. Kelly, 1945-1947 (Box 134, Folder 1277)
    - Stinson v. N.Y. Life Insurance Company, 1946 (Box 134, Folder 1278)
    - Zeigler v. N.Y. Life Insurance Company, 1946 (Box 134, Folder 1278)
    - Bennion v. N.Y. Life Insurance Company, 1945-1947 (Box 134, Folder 1279)
    - Bennion v. N.Y. Life Insurance Company, 1945-1947 (Box 135, Folder 1280)
    - U.S. v. Chemical Foundation Inc., 1925-1926 (Box 135, Folder 1281)
    - City of Coral Gables v. Coral Gables Inc., 1935 (Box 135, Folder 1282-1283)
    - Coyle v. New York State, 1943-1944 (Box 135, Folder 1284)
    - Z. and F. Assets Corp. v. Cordell Hull, et al, 1939 (Box 135, Folder 1285)
    - American Machine & Metals Inc. v. De Bothezat Inc., 1940 (Box 135, Folder 1286)
    - Gerradin v. United Fruit Co. - SS Castilla, 1931-1932 (Box 135, Folder 1287)
    - U.S. v. Chemical Foundation Inc., 1922 (Box 135, Folder 1288)
    - Tidelands Oil Question, 1945 (Box 136, Folder 1289-1291)
    - Patent cases - research notes (Box 136, Folder 1292)
    - Liability cases - research notes (Box 136, Folder 1293)
    - Insurance cases (Box 136, Folder 1294-1295)
    - Bernhard Weiss Case - Nuerenberg, 1948 (Box 136, Folder 1296)
    - General International Organization Charter proposals, 1943-1944 (Box 136, Folder 1297)
    - War Insurance Compensation Bills (Box 136, Folder 1298)
    - Yale Conference on the Press and the War Crisis, 1942 (Box 137, Folder 1299)
    - Finnish loans, 1940 (Box 137, Folder 1300)
    - War damage, 1942 (Box 137, Folder 1301)
    - Lend Lease Bill, 1941 (Box 137, Folder 1302)
    - Dumbarton Oaks proposals - pamphlets, circular letters, 1944-1945 (Box 137, Folder 1303)
    - Executive agreements - correspondence, speeches, 1945 (Box 137, Folder 1304)
    - National conscription, 1945-1946 (Box 137, Folder 1305)
    - National conscription - clippings, 1945-1946 (Box 137, Folder 1306)
    - San Francisco Charter, 1945 (Box 137, Folder 1307)
    - Trading with the Enemy Act - amendment efforts, 1944 (Box 137, Folder 1308)
    - Office of Strategic Services, 1945 (Box 137, Folder 1309)
    - Anti-Poll Tax Bill, 1942-1946 (Box 137, Folder 1310)
    - Atomic Energy Bills - 79th Congress, 1945 (Box 138, Folder 1311)
    - Rumanian oil pipeline expropriation, 1940-1941 (Box 138, Folder 1312)
    - Naturalization and citizenship, 1939-1940 (Box 138, Folder 1313)
    - Wilbur Guest citizenship case, 1936 (Box 138, Folder 1314-1316)
    - United States v. Pink, 1942 (Box 138, Folder 1317)
    - S.S. Drottningholm passengers (Ellis Island), 1942-1943 (Box 138, Folder 1318)
    - Schwarzkopf Case, 1943 (Box 138, Folder 1319)
    - Immigration cases, 1936-1938 (Box 138, Folder 1320)
    - Sommerich, Otto - lectures on problems involving enemy aliens, 1942 (Box 138, Folder 1321)
    - National Council on Naturalization and Citizenship memorandum, newsletters, 1939-1943 (Box 139, Folder 1322)
    - "Codification of the Nationality Laws of the U.S." House Committee Print, 1939 (Box 139, Folder 1323)
    - Immigration and naturalization
      - research notes, memoranda (Box 139, Folder 1324-1327)
    - Immigration, 1942 (Box 139, Folder 1328)
- Writings and Speeches, 1910-1947; Series V; 3' (7 boxes)
  Professor Borchard's writings and speeches are grouped in seven sections according to form. Within each section arrangement is alphabetical, except for Book Reviews and Speeches, which are arranged chronologically.
  Section A: Articles
  Section B: Memoranda
  Section C: Legal Opinions
  Section D: Books
  Section E: Book Reviews
  Section F: Pamphlets
  Section G: Speeches
  - Articles
    - "Access of Individuals to International Courts", undated (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "The Access of Individuals to International Courts", 1930 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Alcuni Aspetti del Diritto Comparato Negli Stati Uniti", 1932 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Alien Private Property", Undated, 1929 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Alien Private Property and American Claims", undated (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - (editorial) (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Alien Property and War Claims", 1926? (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "The Alien Property Custodian", undated (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "America and a Court of Justice for the Nations", 1932 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "The American Claims Against Germany", post-1924 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "American Foreign Policy", undated (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Arbitration, International", 1930 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Armed Merchantmen", post-1939 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "The Arms Embargo and Neutrality", 1933 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "The Attorney General's Opinion on the Exchange of Destroyers for Naval Bases", 1940 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Austrian and Hungarian 'Debt' Claims" (editorial), undated (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Back of the Fall of the Franc" (editorial), 1924 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "Brazilian-United States Diplomatic Relations", 1938 (Box 140, Folder 1329)
    - "The Calvo and Drago Doctrines", 1930 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "The Calvo Doctrine", undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Can the King Do Wrong?", undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Can the State Commit a Tort?", undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "A Century of International Law", 1936 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Challenging 'Penal' Statutes by Declaratory Action", 1943 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Circumstantial Evidence", post-1930 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "The Citizen Abroad", undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Citizenship by Birth in the United States Not Lost Through Naturalization Abroad of Minor's Father"(editorial), 1939? (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "The Citizenship of Native-Born American Women Who Married Foreigners Before March 2, 1907, and Acquired a Foreign Domicile", post-1934 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Codification" (re: opposition to third Hague conference), undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Codification", undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Commentary on General Bill Giving Cause of Action in Tort against the Government", undated (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Comments of Edwin Borchard on the Draft Convention on the Rights and Duties of Neutral States", 1938 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "The Committee of Experts' at the Lima Conference", 1939 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Committee of Experts, Pan-American Codification of International Law"(editorial), 1937 (Box 140, Folder 1330)
    - "Common Sense in Foreign Policy", 1920 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Community Liability for Civilian War Injuries", 1942 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "The Conference for American Intervention in a European War" (editorial), 1934 (Box 140, Folder 1331)
    - "Confiscation", (editorial) (Box 140, Folder 1331)